Guide to the William A. Reuben Papers TAM.289
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
William A. Reuben Papers
1923-2003
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Reuben, William A.
Reuben, William H.
TAM.289
22.5 Linear Feet (24 boxes)
William A. Reuben (1916-2004) was a graduate of Columbia University and a World War II combat veteran. After the war Reuben began his career as an investigative journalist. Reuben's first book on the Alger Hiss trials, The Honorable Mr. Nixon, was published in 1956. Shortly after this, Reuben began his reexamination of the Hiss case evidence, a task that would occupy him for the rest of his life. In 1974, as part of this work, he filed a Freedom of Information Act request for FBI documents related to the case. The release of such documents, and the information they provided, enabled Alger Hiss to prepare a lawsuit seeking to overturn his conviction based on an alleged pattern of misconduct by the Bureau and the prosecutor, Thomas F. Murphy. The collection consists of correspondence, reference materials, drafts of several unpublished book-length works by Reuben, copies of FBI and other government files, and copies of court records. Also included are one box of audiotapes and one boxes of research notes.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by William A. Reuben and William H. Reuben in 2002; additional materials were donated by William H. Reuben in 201. The accession numbers associated with these gifts are 2002.003 and 2010.057.
Arrangement
Folders (and cards) are arranged alphabetically by topic in Series I-IV.
Organized in six series:
Missing Title
Series I: Alger Hiss Materials, 1948-1994.
Series II: Subject Files, 1923-2003.
Series III: Files Obtained under the Freedom of Information Act, 1930s-1970s.
Series IV: Note Cards, Undated.
Series V: Audio Cassettes, 1948-1996.
Series VI: USA v. Alger Hiss, 1949.
Historical/Biographical Note
William A. Reuben (1916-2004) was born in Cleveland, Ohio and educated at the Wharton School, the University of Pennsylvania and Columbia University (Graduate Faculty of English). Reuben served as a lieutenant with the 45th Infantry Division in World War II and received three Purple Hearts.After the war Reuben began his career as an investigative journalist and later served as national publicity director for the American Civil Liberties Union. He wrote numerous articles for Scribner's, Vogue, the National Guardian, the Nation and Rights, the journal of the National Emergency Civil Liberties Foundation and published a number of books and pamphlets, including, "To Secure Justice in the Rosenberg Case" (1951); The Atom Spy Hoax(New York: Action Books, 1955); The Honorable Mr. Nixon and the Alger Hiss Case(New York: Action Books, 1956); The Mark Fein Case(New York: Dial Press, 1967); and "Footnote on an Historic Case: In Re Alger Hiss, No. 78 Civ. 3433" (New York: The Nation Institute, 1983).
As a founder and Provisional Chairman of the Committee to Secure Justice in the Rosenberg Case, Reuben was active in the endeavor to bring national attention to the cases of Ethel and Julius Rosenberg and Morton Sobell. Shortly after publication of The Honorable Mr. Nixon, Reuben began his reexamination of the Hiss case evidence, a task that would occupy him for the rest of his life. In 1974, as part of this work, he filed a Freedom of Information Act request for FBI documents related to the case. In the lawsuit growing out of this request, filed by the New York City firm of Rabinowitz, Boudin and Standard, and sponsored by the National Emergency Civil Liberties Foundation, the plaintiffs obtained more than 300,000 pages of copies of documents from the files of the FBI and other agencies. The release of these documents, and the information they provided, enabled Alger Hiss to prepare a lawsuit aimed at overturning his conviction, based on an alleged pattern of misconduct by the Bureau and the prosecutor, Thomas F. Murphy. Although Hiss's petition did not prevail, the thousands of documents released by the government offered an invaluable look at the politics and tactics of J. Edgar Hoover's FBI in the 1940s and 1950s.
William Reuben died of natural causes on Monday, May 31, 2004, in New York City, at the age of 88.
Other Finding Aids
The microfilmed portion of this collection (Series I, Box 1) and the microfilmed portions of several other collections related to Alger Hiss at this repository form the microfilm edition of the Papers of Alger Hiss (comprised of Film R-7771B, R-7771C, R-7771D, and R-7771E). A published guide to the Papers of Alger Hiss microfilm edition is available at this repository (call number REF E743.5.H55 P38 2006).
Related Archival Material
Related materials providing biographical information on Alger Hiss and information on the Hiss case can be found in the following collections in this repository (researchers must use microfilm where indicated):
Agnese Nelms Haury Papers, TAM 163 (Series 1, Boxes 1 and 2 on microfilm, Film R-7771D)
John Lowenthal Papers, TAM 190 (Series 1, Boxes 1-5 on microfilm, Film R-7771C)
Alger Hiss Family Papers, TAM 314 (on microfilm, Film R-7771B: Series 1, Boxes 1-3; Series 2, Boxes 4-5; and Series 3, Box 6)
A published guide to the microfilmed portions of these collections is available at this repository (call number REF E743.5.H55 P38 2006).
The Alger Hiss Defense Collection housed at the Harvard Law School Library, Harvard University consists of 115 boxes of materials amassed by Hiss's lawyers and additional materials related to Hiss's defense donated by Hiss researchers and supporters. The first three series of the Alger Hiss Defense Collection (Hiss Defense Files Series I, Hiss Defense Files Series II, and Hiss-Chambers Subject Files) are available at this repository on microfilm (Film R-7771A) and have an associated published guide (call number REF E743.5.H55 P37 2006). Materials excluded from the microfilm are available to researchers who use the collection on site at the Harvard Law School Library at Harvard University.
Scope and Content Note
Series I: Alger Hiss Materials, 1948-1994, contains correspondence with Alger, Isabel and Tony Hiss, correspondence regarding Whittaker Chambers, and other correspondence between Reuben and scholars, journalists, research assistants and others interested in the Hiss Case. The collection also includes research materials pertaining to the Hiss Case. Note: Series I. Alger Hiss Materials, 1948-1994 was microfilmed as part of the collection, "Alger Hiss Papers at the Tamiment Library," (Thomson Gale Publishers). NOTE: Researchers should use the microfilm (R-7771E).
Series II: Subject Files, 1923-2003, consists primarily of material gathered in the course of Reuben's research on Alger Hiss and Whittaker Chambers, including Edward H. Fearon's trial evidence regarding the Hiss family's Woodstock typewriter, files on the history of espionage, legal records pertaining to Reuben's and Hiss's attempts to obtain the release of government documents, and several drafts of Reuben's unpublished manuscripts on Hiss and Chambers..
Series III: Files Obtained under the Freedom of Information Act (FOIA), 1930s-1970s. Most of these materials were obtained by attorney Victor Rabinowitz in response to his FOIA requests and litigation on behalf of Alger Hiss and/or William Reuben. The series also contains redacted FBI and other government files collected by William Reuben during his research for the Hiss and Chambers manuscripts.
Series IV: Note Cards, Undated. One box of handwritten and typed note cards relating to individuals and subjects of interest to Reuben for his research for the Hiss and Chambers manuscripts, as well as notes for other research projects and articles.
Series V: Audio Cassettes, 1948-1996. This series contains 46 audiotapes including 30 cassette tapes and sixteen micro-cassettes. Eighteen of the cassette tapes are identified as being interviews and radio programs collected by William Reuben, including Reuben presenting at the University of New York, Paul Berman interviewing Ronald Radosh and presentations by Sender Garlin and Michael Parenti at the University of Colorado; twelve of the cassette tapes are unlabelled. Nine micro-cassettes are labeled as containing interviews Reuben conducted with Raisha Vasilievna and Professors Dubovsky and Goldvin in Moscow, and with Grete Fuchs in Dresden; seven of the micro-cassettes are unlabeled.
Series VI: U.S.A. v. Alger Hiss, 1949. This box of court transcripts from Alger Hiss's first trial consists of copies of material also found in the John Lowenthal Papers (Tamiment #190).
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Series I, Box 1 of the collection is available on microfilm (Film R-7771E) for use in this repository only. Researchers must use microfilm for this portion of the collection.
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Communists -- United States.; Personal papers.; Articles.; Communism -- United States.; Drafts (documents); Audiotapes.; Hiss, Alger; Nixon, Richard M. (Richard Milhous), 1913-1994; Tanenhaus, Sam; Weinstein, Allen; Lockwood, Agnese Nelms; American Civil Liberties Union; Rosenberg, Julius, 1918-1953; Hughes, Langston, 1902-1967; Communist Party of the United States of America; Lowenthal, John, 1925-2003; Chambers, Whittaker; Gouzenko, Igor, 1919-1982; Craig, R. Bruce.; Navasky, Victor S.; Rabinowitz, Victor; Hiss, Tony; Reuben, William A.; Hiss, Priscilla Fansler; Robeson, Paul, 1898-1976; Rosenberg, Ethel, 1915-1953; Hiss, Isabel Johnson; Reuben, William H.
- Series I. Alger Hiss Materials 1948-1994.
  - Altman, George, 1957-1958, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Chambers, Whittaker: Correspondence re:, undated, 1957-1969, 1974, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Counterattack, Excerpts, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Craig, Bruce, undated, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - DeLeon, Solon: Re: Whittaker Chambers, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Eisendrath, David, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Fearon, Edward, H: Typewriter Evidence, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Freedom of Information Act (FOIA) Litigation, 1981-1992 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Goldin, Frances, 1984, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Gwynn, Beatrice: Translation of Article by Italian Journalist Augusto Marcelli re: Hiss, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Hensel, Philip S.: "Alger Hiss as I Knew Him at Johns Hopkins" (typescript), Aug 1984 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Hiss, Alger: Correspondence, undated, 1972, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Hiss, Isabel Johnson, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Hiss, Tony, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Hiss Case: Typewriter, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Morton, Robin: Re: Whittaker Chambers, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Series II. Subject Files, 1923-2003.
  - ABC News Close-Up: J. Edgar Hoover Program, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - ABC's Old News: Editorial re: Rosenberg Trial ( The Nation), 1982 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Abt, John, 1949, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Action Books:, 1953-1960, 1985, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Action Books: FOIA Request, 1977-1992 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Adams, Eric: Canadian Government Reports, re:, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Alger Hiss Defense Fund, undated, 1949-1950 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - The Alliance, undated, 1996-1997 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Altman, George: Memoranda, 1957-1958 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - American Civil Liberties Union, undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - American Historical Association: Correspondence re: Allen Weinstein, undated, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Analysis of the Post-World War II "Spy" Cases: Typescript (WR), undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Anti-Communism and the United States: Paper Proposal (WR), undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Aronson, James: Correspondence and Writings, undated, 1980-1987 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Articles and Writing: The Nation, 1984-1987 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Articles and Writing: The National Guardian, 1986, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Articles and Writing: Other, undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Articles and Writing: Rights, 1985-1988, 1993-1995 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Atom Spy Hoax: Reviews, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - The Atom Spy Plot That Never Was: A Study in Cold War Disinformation: Book Proposal, undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Authors League of America: The Authors League Fund, 1974, 1979, 1993-1999 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Bedacht, Max: Notes, re:, undated, 1940s (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Belfrage, Cedric and Sally, undated, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Belfrage, Cedric: Opinion of Edward Weinfeld, undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Berle, Adolph A.: Correspondence, 1963-1971 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Berle, Adolph A.: Memoranda, re:, 1941-1952 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Berle, Adolph A.: Notes, re:, 1930s-1970s (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Binger, Carl, undated, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Biographical Material (W.R.), undated, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Boucot, Joseph, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Boudin, Leonard, Kathy and Jean, undated, 1974, 1979-1990 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Boyle, Joe: Whittaker Chambers, re:, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Breindel, Eric, 1990s (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Bridges, Harry: Trial, undated (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Brooks, John: The Big Wheel, Correspondence, re:, Feb 21, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Browder, Earl Russell, 1940s-1960s (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Brown, Lawrence: Memorial, Feb 11, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Budenz, Louis, 1940s, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Bykov, Boris, 1940s (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Caleb and Julia Dula Educational and Charitable Foundation, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Cameron, Angus: Correspondence, 1942-1943 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Cameron, Angus: Memorial, Feb 1, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Cantwell, Robert, undated (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Carnegie Fund for Authors, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Carpenter, David: Interview and Notes, undated, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Case, Edward W: Westminster, Maryland, re:, undated (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Catlett, Michael and Family, undated, 1940s (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Central Intelligence Agency, 1975-1976 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Chafee, Zacharia: Correspondence, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Chaly, Ingeborg: "Pounding the Critical Gavel: Rhetorical Ruling on Judges Kaufman and Goddard", May 1979 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Chaly, Ingeborg: "Rhetorical Discretion and Legal Constraints in Jury Instructions: A Comparative Analysis of the Two Charges to the Jury in the Alger Hiss Trials", Spring 1982 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Chamber of Commerce: Notes, re:, 1940s (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Chambers Article: The Guardian and New York Times, undated (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Chambers Article: "'Spy' Story of Whittaker Chambers", undated (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Chambers, Esther: Testimony and Notes, re:, undated, 1940s, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Chambers Family: Correspondence and Notes, re:, undated, 1968-1969 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Chambers Family: Death Certificates and Wills, 1923, 1931, 1968-1971 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Chambers Film Script: "Whittaker Chambers: An American Hero", undated, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Chambers, Jay, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Chambers, Laha, undated, 1958-1959, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Chambers Manuscript: Preface, Undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Chambers Manuscript: Introduction, undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Chambers Manuscript: Introduction and Preface, Notes, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Chambers Manuscript: Introduction/Preface, Notes, undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Chambers Manuscript: Part 1, The Drama, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Chambers Manuscript: Chapter 1, Introduction by Way of a Biographer's Complaint, Undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Chambers Manuscript: Chapter 1, Our Man in Lynbrook, undated (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Chambers Manuscript: Chapter 2, undated (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Chambers Manuscript: Chapter 2, The Grand Jury Charges, undated (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Chambers Manuscript: Chapter 2, The Palest Ink is Better than the Best Memory, Undated (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Chambers Manuscript: Chapter 2, The Witness, undated (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Chambers Manuscript: Chapter 3, undated (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Chambers Manuscript: Chapter 3, Family Portrait, undated (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Chambers Manuscript: Chapter 3, Inserts, undated (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Chambers Manuscript: Chapter 3, Notes, undated (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Chambers Manuscript: Chapter 4, Notes, undated (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Chambers Manuscript: Chapter 4, Vivian, undated (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Chambers Manuscript: Chapter 5, undated (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Chambers Manuscript: Chapter 5, South Side High, undated (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Chambers Manuscript: Chapter 6, Portrait of the Spy as a Young Writer, undated (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Chambers Manuscript: Chapter 7, The Last Days of Vivian, undated (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Chambers Manuscript: Chapter 8, Other Voices, Other Rooms, undated (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Chambers Manuscript: Chapter 9, Morningside, undated (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Chambers Manuscript: Chapter 10, A Play for Puppets, undated (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Chambers Manuscript: Chapter 11, Richard, undated (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Chambers Manuscript: Chapter 11, Turning Point, undated (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Chambers Manuscript: Chapter 12, Secret Work, undated (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Chambers Manuscript: Chapter 13, Inserts, undated (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Chambers Manuscript: Chapter 13, Morningside Revisited, undated (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Chambers Manuscript: Chapter 14, The Functionary, undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Chambers Manuscript: Chapter 14, Inserts, undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Chambers Manuscript: Chapter 14, Party Functionary, undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Chambers Manuscript: Chapter 15, undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Chambers Manuscript: Chapter 15, Inserts, undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Chambers Manuscript: Chapter 16, Drafts and Notes, undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Chambers Manuscript: Chapter 16, Isaac Don Levine, Stage Manager, undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Chambers Manuscript: A. A. Berle HUAC Testimony, undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Chambers Manuscript: Biographies and Chronology, undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Chambers Manuscript: Chambers and Dostoevsky, undated (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Chambers Manuscript: Chambers Personality, undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Chambers Manuscript: Chronology, undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Chambers Manuscript: Communist Party, undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Chambers Manuscript: Correspondence re: (Random House), 1950s-1960s (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Chambers Manuscript: The Dream of Whittaker Chambers, Table of Contents, undated (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Chambers Manuscript: Eugene Dennis, undated (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Chambers Manuscript: Frank McNaughton, Correspondence, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Chambers Manuscript: Laha Chambers, undated (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Chambers Manuscript: Louis Zukovsky, 1967-1968 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Chambers Manuscript: Nathaniel Ross, undated, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Chambers Manuscript: New Masses Chapter, undated (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Chambers Manuscript: Notes, undated (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Chambers Manuscript: Peter Shepherd's Comments re:, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Chambers Manuscript: Recollections of Classmates, undated, 1969, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Chambers Manuscript: Time, Notes re:, undated, 1939 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Chambers Manuscript: Underground, undated (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Chambers Manuscript: Witness, Notes re:, undated (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Chambers, Richard, undated, 1960s (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Chambers, Whittaker: Baltimore, Maryland, Sep 30, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Chambers, Whittaker: Break with Communist Party, 1929, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Chambers, Whittaker: "Can You Make Out Their Voices" ( New Masses), Mar 2007 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Chambers, Whittaker: Cold Friday, Excerpts and Notes, undated (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Chambers, Whittaker: Columbia University, undated (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Chambers, Whittaker: FBI Interviews, May 1950-Nov 1950 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Chambers, Whittaker: FBI Report, re: Time, 1945 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Chambers, Whittaker: Fiction of, Notes re:, undated (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Chambers, Whittaker: George Crossley, Aug 1948 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Chambers, Whittaker: Homosexuality, undated, 1949 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Chambers, Whittaker: Lynbrook High School, 1968-1969 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Chambers, Whittaker: Mental Health, undated, Jun 24, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Chambers, Whittaker: New Masses, Sep 9, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Chambers, Whittaker: Notes re:, undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Chambers, Whittaker: Primary and Secondary Schools, undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Chambers, Whittaker: Religiosity, undated, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Chambers, Whittaker: Residences, undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Chambers, Whittaker: Simon and Schuster, 1938-1939 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Chambers, Whittaker: Time, 1940s (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Chambers, Whittaker: Timeline, 1920s-1930s (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Chambers, Whittaker: Translations, Notes, undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Chambers, Whittaker: Williams College, 1968-1969 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Chambers, Whittaker: Workers School, undated, 1926-1928 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Chambers, Whittaker: Writings, 1920s-1930s (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Charterhouse Books Incorporated, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Civil Liberties Department: Proposals to Various American Magazines, 1946-1947 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Clark, Tom: United States Attorney General, 1948-1950, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Cleveland, Richard: Correspondence, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Clippings: Re: Reuben, 1980s (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Clubb, O. Edmond, 1950s-1970s (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Cohn, Roy: Writings re:, 1955, 1986, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Committee to Secure Justice in the Rosenberg Case, 1952 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Communism: Legal Opinions, Notes, 1940s (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Communist Party of Canada: Notes, undated (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Communist Party, USA, 1949 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Conference: Rosenberg Case Revisited, Jul 2007 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Conspiracy: Quotes of Interest, 1960s (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Cook, Fred, undated, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Cornell University: Libraries, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence, 1998-2003 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Cowley, Michael: Clippings, Correspondence, Notes, re:, 1940s, 1969, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Craig, Bruce, 1997-1998 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Craig, Bruce: "Politics in the Pumpkin Patch," Whittaker Chambers' Farm Designated a Historical Site, undated (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Crichton, Robert: Correspondence, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - The Crime of Dr. Soblen: Synopsis, undated (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Cronin, John F.: Correspondence and Memoranda, 1950s, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Cronin, John F.: "The Problem of American Communism in 1945: Facts and Recommendations" (excerpts), undated (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Cross, Claude, 1952, 1962, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Damaz, Paul, Annie and Guillon, 1979, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Darling, Maus V., undated, 1948-1950 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Darling, Maus V.: Memoirs re: Whittaker Chambers, undated, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Department of Justice: Correspondence, 1960s-1970s (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Department of Justice: FBI, 1974-1978 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Department of Justice: Privacy Act Request, undated, 1975-1977 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Deportation from Canada (WR), 1955 (Box 5, Folder 42)